<deck>
  <slide id="tiles">
    <lede>Laying out a slide with tiles</lede>
    <tile top="100" width="960">
      <tile width="400">
        <p>Once you're in a slide, you can lay out the contents of the
        slide through tiles. A <b>tile</b> element represents an area of content which
        you can position on the slide by specifying position and width.
        Inside the tile you can place text and pictures. There are some
        elements that can be positioned directly on the slide without
        being wrapped in tiles, this is a convenience for common cases.</p>
        <p>You can indicate the position of a tile with the attributes
        <code>top, bottom, left,</code> and <code>right</code>. These
        work the same (and translate to) as the CSS attributes. The
        attributes take an integer value, which corresponds to css
        pixels. You shouldn't use both top and bottom (or both left and
        right) for the same tile.</p>
        <p>The default slide dimensions I use are 960 px wide and 590px
        tall. Combined with a banner of 30px along the top this results
        in a slide size that fits well on iPads. The aspect ratio won't
        work as well for other devices, but slides will still display
        with some wasted space. The notion of a deck relies on laying
        out elements in two dimensions, so it's very tricky to produce a
        layout that would truly flex to different apsect ratios. </p>
        <p>There is a width attribute (again in pixels) which you can
        use to set the width of a tile. It defaults to 300px.</p>
      </tile>
      <tile left="450">
        <p>Tiles can be nested. I'm using this here to give two tiles
        the same <code>top</code> without duplicating the attribute </p>
      </tile>
    </tile>
    <tile class="sidebar" bottom="10" right="20">
      <p>The defaults for dimensions are set out in the base scss
      file: <code>mfweb-dir/lib/mfweb/ infodeck/infodeck.scss</code>.
      Like any other part of the CSS it can be changed either for a
      whole site or a single deck.</p>
    </tile>
  </slide>
</deck>